DAVID CERI ROBERTS

PROFILE

I am an affable, motivated person with a strong educational background. A **Masters in Coastal & Marine Resource Management** and **an Honours Degree in Geography** illustrate my passion for learning, ability to research material and write extended reports on findings. Having worked in education for the past 10 Years I am now looking for a fresh challenge in a new field.

Through my time at University and in the workplace I have developed a wide knowledge base (in Geography, Research methods and ICT) coupled with a very useful skill-set including ICT, research, time management, interpersonal skills and written / oral presentation skills.

CAREER HISTORY

2015 - 2018 Lingfield College - Head of Geography

- Day to day management of the Geography department and teaching all age groups.
- Long term planning, ensuring schemes of work are written to a high standard.
- Preparation and sharing of resources.
- Tracking pupil progress, identifying underachievement and notifying staff and parents as appropriate.
- Ensuring staff have access to the training they need to develop.
- Setting department meeting agendas and chairing meetings.
- Organised, led and attended numerous field trips.

2009 – 2015 The Marist Schools - Teacher of Geography

- Responsible for teaching Geography to all age groups.
- Acting Head of Department for Geography during maternity leave responsible for two nonspecialists at that time.
- Written several schemes of work for all Key Stages and provided / created hundreds of resources to support them.
- Strong pastoral involvement as a Year 8 tutor teaching PSHE and as a Head of House.
- Involvement in the wider-school community through field trips, concerts and drama.

2002 - 2008 BP Marine Ltd - UK Order Manager

- Responsible for organising and arranging the supply of BP Marine lubricants around the world.
- As the penalty for errors is very high the work is very pressured and the position is definitely one of great responsibility.
- Skilled at time management due to working with different time zones.
- Super-user for several systems which entailed the dissemination of acquired knowledge to other team members (sometimes at remote locations).

2001 - 2002 The Highways Agency - Project Support Administrator

- Working as part of an Accounts Production Team.
- Designated Cost Centre Purchasing Officer responsible for the tracking of all expenses, claims and invoices.

1997 - 1998 Black Horse Agencies - Regional Human Resources Administrator

- Ability to handle delicate information and situations with responsibility and skill
- Liaised with multiple locations/personnel within the region.

EDUCATION

2008 - 2009 St. Mary's College University PGCE in Secondary Geography

1999 - 2000 University of Portsmouth Master of Science in Coastal and Marine Resource Management

Developed sound knowledge of coastal and marine environmental issues, resource
management, valuation techniques, and related policy and legislation. Evaluated the multiple
pressures placed upon the coastal zone in relation to physical processes, human activities
and the link between the two.

1994 - 1997 University of London (Royal Holloway College) Honours Degree in Geography - B.Sc. 2.1

Modular course covering all aspects of Geography. Bias towards physical side over human
but with all processes and landforms linked back to their impact on populations and
settlement. Acquired knowledge and research methods were used for Fieldwork in Almeria,
Spain and Drymen, Scotland. First Class awarded for Independent Dissertation undertaken
in Snowdonia involving the field testing of the Schmidt Hammer.

1989 - 1994 Berkhamsted School, Berkhamsted, Herts

GCSE: Geography A Geology A English Language A Physics A French A
English Literature A Chemistry B Mathematics B Biology B History B
Art & Design C

A Level (June 1994): Chemistry C Biology B Geography B A Level (June 1999): Film Studies A (West Herts - Cassio Campus)

Bronze, Silver, and Gold award in Duke of Edinburgh award scheme.

<u>INTERESTS</u>

I am interested in all culture particularly film and theatre. All genres of film interest me so I watch indie and art films together with the more mainstream fare. Theatre has always been a passion and I go to see the smaller productions Off-West End as well as the bigger star-studded West End shows. I also go and see quite a lot of stand-up comedy. My Current favourites are Daniel Kitson and John Robins. I have an eclectic taste in music ranging from The Animals to Zero 7. In terms of sport, I am a keen Racket Sports player (particularly Squash and Table Tennis) and an even keener Rugby watcher (Wasps and Wales).

Contact: 1 Eagle Close Date of Birth: 19 Feb 1976

Uckfield, East Sussex, TN22 5WL Marital Status: Married

(01825) 767 745 Dependents: Two (Isabelle & Joshua)

(07745) 392 952 (mobile) email: cezroberts@hotmail.com